

Salah eddin el kabli

Address: paris, France

Email: salah.hda@gmail.com | Telephone: +33668625038

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Efficient, organized DevOps with 10 years of experience and a record of working to very high standards. Proven literacy and numeracy skills – proficient user of Linux systems and AWS/GCP public cloud, Holds an extensive skill and a positive attitude to professional development. Excels in collaboration; possesses a proven record of inspiring others in different environments. Manage meetings and events effectively, and able to resolve difficult technical challenges.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

08/2022 - present

Docapost

Paris

Senior Devops/SRE

- Design and Secure infra on Cloud
- Create Infra as a code with Terraform
- Automate apps deployment using ansible, Terraform
- Dockerize apps
- Automate repetitive tasks using Python and bash.
- Manage and troubleshoot apps on Kubernetes clusters,
- Troubleshoot and resolve incidents on Kubernetes environments
- Improve monitoring and logging Systems
- Automate deployment on k8s using Helm and flux
- Ci/CD as a code using Jenkins builder

09/2019 - 07/2022

Carrefour

Paris

Senior SRE

- Design and Secure infra on Cloud
- Create Infra as a code with Terraform
- Automate apps deployment using ansible, Terraform
- Dockerize apps

- Automate deployment on GCP
- Manage and troubleshoot apps on GKE,
- Troubleshoot issues on GCP
- Deploy and configure monitoring Systems
- Automate deployment on k8s using Helm
- Ci/CD pipelines implementation using Jenkins
- Python, bash coding

02/2020 - 08/2022

Sapien

USA

Senior DevOps engineer

- Design infra on Cloud
- Create Infra as a code with Terraform
- Secure and management of infra on AWS
- Automate apps and infra deployment
- Dokerize blockchain apps,
- Design Multi CICD process using gitlab-ci,
- Monitor/logging apps on eks using Prometheus, alertmanager, Grafana and loki

07/2019 - 02/2021

EdgeSec

USA

Devsecops engineer

- Create Infra as a code with Terraform
- Secure and management of infra on AWS
- Automate apps and infra deployment using ansible, Terraform
- Automate Vulnerability Scanner deployment on Aws and on promise
- Manage and troubleshoot apps on aws,
- Python, bash coding
- Deploy and configure monitoring Systems
- Secure servers on Aws and on promise
- Ci/CD pipelines implementation using Jenkins
- Help Clients securing there environment, deployment and secure apps on AWS

03/2019 - 09/2019

SOFRECOM

MOROCCO

SENIOR DEVOPS engineer

- Create Infra as a code with Terraform
- deploy high available Kubernetes cluster on premise
- automate Kubernetes deployments with ansible
- CI/CD pipelines integrations with multi stages
- containerize applications
- automate app deployments using ansible
- implementation monitoring and logging solutions (Prometheus/Grafana, elk stack)

05/2018 - 02/2019

Alphanetworks

Belgium

Linux System integrator consultant

- Install, configure Linux solutions
- automate infra deployments using ansible
- manage linux platforms
- Deploy kubernetes on GCP
- Install and manade deployments under Jboss-eap clusters
- Install and Manage applications cluster(zend, JBOSS-EAP)
- deploy and configure load balancers/proxies(nginx,ha-proxy,waf)
- ssl encryption (letsencrypt)
- manage kubernetes cluster

03/2017 - 09/2019

HOOLIA EUROPE

Netherlands

DEVOPS engineer

- Install and manage OPENSHIFT clusters
- Help clients migrate there apps to OpenShift solution
- CI/CD
- Automation :
 - * Terraform
 - * Ansible
 - * Packer
- Cloud platforms
 - * google cloud platform (GCP)
 - * AWS platform
 - * ESX platform

07/2017 - 05/2018

Mobinets

Casablanca, Morocco

System integrator engineer

- Installation & configuration of GEMALTO products under RHEEL.
- Administration of virtualization solutions (vmWare vcloud director, vCenter, ESXi).
- Administration and optimization of Linux servers (security).
- Administration of MySQL servers (security and optimization).
- Administration of web environments (Loadbalancer, hight availability cluster reverse proxy, Apache).
- Administration of file sharing and messaging servers.
- Administration of the management servers (Backup, Logging, Monitoring, Authentication).
- Perform audits on systems and application layers.
- Writing installation and operating documentation for the various application products.
- Management and implementation of projects (Design, Reports, Schematics, Planning).
- Firewall & VPN configuration
- Network configuration.
- Customer support.
- Automation of log backups.
- Scripting using bash.
- solve various system related problems (database, networks, security)
- Locate and diagnose faults and anomalies.
- Assist remote clients to solve problems encountered.
- Administration system (RHEEL / CENT OS).

04/2017 - 07/2017

NTM

Casablanca

System Administrator

- Install and maintain solution under Linux OS
- Support level 1 & 2
- Install and Configure Monitoring system (icinga2, Grafana)
- Configuration of Buck up server (rsync, backup pc, rs napshot)
- Automate solution deployment using Ansible

04/2014 - 04/2017

TLSCONTACT

Casablanca, Morocco

IT operations engineer

- Design and installation of the network infrastructure of the Casablanca, Rabat, Fes, Tangier, Agadir, Marrakech and Oujda sites
- Switch configuration (catalyst 2960 series) & firewalls (ASA 5505, 5506).
- $\hbox{- Installation and configuration of Juniper SSG-140-SH firewalls, Cisco switches, Cisco AP-Wifi.}\\$
- Configuring web filtering server under Cent os.
- VPN configuration.
- Preparations for ISO 27001 VAC certification.
- IP migration for multiple sites.
- Installation and configuration of ESXI (VMware).

- Installing and configuring ACTIVE DIRECTORY server.
- Configure GPO rules.
- Installation and configuration of the video surveillance system (Axis).
- Installation and configuration of the access control system (Suprema).
- Participate in optimizing the offers and resources allocated.
- Conduct weekly, monthly, and quarterly security audits.
- Remote technical support for the sites of Tunis, Egypt, Lebanon, England, South Africa, Niger.
- Responsible for purchasing and negotiating with suppliers.
- Make inventories of Casablanca, Rabat, Fez, Tangier, Marrakech, and Agadir sites.
- Find solutions to help operations.
- VPN configuration

EDUCATION

07/2012 - 09/2013

AIX Marseille

Marseille, France

bachelor: Computer science

09/2010 - 06/2012

OFPPT

Meknes, Morocco

Bac+2: Networks and systems techniques

Certified:

CKA: Certified Kubernetes Admin

RHCSA: Red Hat certied system administrator

RHCSE: Red hat certified system engineer

INTERESTS

Skiing, travelling, learning new skills.